Guide to the William Kent Family Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- WRITINGS, 1873-1929, undated; Series II; 2.50' (6 boxes)
  - General
    - War on special interests, 1910 July (Box 59, Folder 186)
    - Letter to the editor - Sacramento Union, 1910 (Box 59, Folder 187)
    - "What about the Packers?", 1918 April (Box 59, Folder 188)
    - "What Might Have Been Said at New York Dinner", 1911 January (Box 59, Folder 189)
    - "What War Has Done and Is Doing", 1915 (Box 59, Folder 190)
    - "The White Man's Burden", undated (Box 59, Folder 191)
    - "Why the Coyote Smiles", 1887 February (Box 59, Folder 192)
    - "The Wine Tax Bill", 1916 July (Box 59, Folder 193)
    - Woodrow Wilson, 1914 March (Box 59, Folder 194)
    - Fragments and notes, undated (Box 59, Folder 195-196)
  - Scrapbooks
    - A - D, 1892-1914, undated (Box 60, Folder 197)
    - E - L, 1892-1907, undated (Box 60, Folder 198)
    - M - S, 1891-1901, undated (Box 60, Folder 199)
    - T - Y, 1890-1914, undated (Box 60, Folder 200)
    - Letters to editors, 1897-1914, undated (Box 60, Folder 201)
    - Group communications, 1895-1904, undated (Box 60, Folder 202)
    - Miscellaneous and incomplete, 1892-1914, undated (Box 60, Folder 203-207)
- TOPICAL FILES, 1846-1952; Series III; 8' (20 boxes)
  This series is arranged in alphabetical order by topic.
  - Business papers, 1905-1927 (Box 61, Folder 1-4)
  - California
    - Council for Progress, 1923-1924 (Box 61, Folder 5)
    - Marin County, 1911-1952, undated (Box 61, Folder 6-11)
  - Camp, Walter, 1917 (Box 61, Folder 12)
  - Campaigns, Political
    - 1910 (Box 62, Folder 13-16)
    - 1912 (Box 62, Folder 17-20)
    - 1914 (Box 62, Folder 21-22)
    - 1916 (Box 62, Folder 23-24)
    - 1918 (Box 62, Folder 25)
    - 1920 (Box 63, Folder 26-33)
    - 1924 (Box 63, Folder 34)
  - Chicago, Illinois
    - Politics, 1896-1914 (Box 63, Folder 35-38)
    - Politics, 1895-1908, undated (Box 64, Folder 39)
    - Writings, undated (Box 64, Folder 40-41)
    - Miscellaneous, 1893-1958 (Box 64, Folder 42-43)
  - Civil liberties, 1918-1942 (Box 64, Folder 44)
  - Congressional legislation, 1903-1927 (Box 64, Folder 45-47)
    See also: box 80, folder 242
  - Conservation
    - Tamplais Park, 1903-1927 (Box 64, Folder 48-49)
    - General, 1911-1927 (Box 64, Folder 50-51)
    - General, 1947, 1949 (Box 65, Folder 52)
    - Oil, 1915-1924 (Box 65, Folder 53)
    - Alaskan coal, 1911-1914 (Box 65, Folder 54)
    - Muir Woods, 1908-1945 (Box 65, Folder 55-56)
    - National and state parks, 1914-1947 (Box 65, Folder 57-59)
    - Redwoods, 1919-1951 (Box 65, Folder 60-62)
    - Public lands, 1912-1916 (Box 65, Folder 63)
    - Alaska, 1911 (Box 65, Folder 64)
    - Alaska, 1911 (Box 66, Folder 65)
    - National forests and the public domain, 1925 (Box 66, Folder 66)
    - Public lands, 1908-1925 (Box 66, Folder 67-74)
    - Water power
      - General, 1902-1917 (Box 66, Folder 75-77)
      - General, 1911-1923 (Box 67, Folder 78-82)
      - Hetch Hetchy, 1912-1944 (Box 67, Folder 83-85)
      - Hetch Hetchy, 1908-1924 (Box 68, Folder 86-91)
      - Lake Tahoe, 1909-1937 (Box 68, Folder 92a-95)
      - Sutter Basin, 1913-1916 (Box 69, Folder 96-97)
      - Marin Municipal Water District, 1906-1938 (Box 69, Folder 98-106)
      - California Water and Power Act, 1922-1924 (Box 69, Folder 107-110)
      - California Water and Power Act, 1917-1924 (Box 70, Folder 111-113)
      - Federal water power policy, 1909-1928 (Box 70, Folder 114a-123)
      - Federal water power policy, 1905-1947 (Box 71, Folder 124-132)
      - Federal water power policy, 1914-1915 (Box 72, Folder 133)
  - Currency reform and the Federal Reserve Act, 1911-1913 (Box 72, Folder 134-135)
  - Japanese question, 1911-1941 (Box 72, Folder 136-137)
  - Jones, Jenkin Lloyd, 1909-1921 (Box 72, Folder 138)
  - Kent, Roger, 1948-1950 (Box 72, Folder 139)
  - Meat packing industry, 1916-1925 (Box 72, Folder 140-143)
  - Meat packing industry, 1912-1925 (Box 73, Folder 144-150)
  - Mexico, 1913-1914 (Box 73, Folder 151)
  - National Popular Government League, 1927-1952 (Box 73, Folder 152-153)
  - National Woman's Party, 1917-1948 (Box 73, Folder 154-155)
  - National Woman's Party, 1911-1952 (Box 74, Folder 156-160)
  - Nursery inspection bill, 1911-1915 (Box 74, Folder 161-163)
  - No folder (Box 74, Folder 164)
  - Obituaries, 1928-1929, 1942 (Box 74, Folder 165)
  - Peace literature, 1915-1951 (Box 74, Folder 166-169)
  - Peace literature, 1917-1946 (Box 75, Folder 170-181)
  - Peace literature, 1912-1952 (Box 76, Folder 182-192)
  - Peace literature, 1935-1951 (Box 77, Folder 193-207)
  - Peace literature, 1919-1945 (Box 78, Folder 208-221)
  - Panama Pacific Exposition, 1913 (Box 79, Folder 222)
  - Panama Canal tolls, 1900-1914 (Box 79, Folder 223)
  - Tariffs
    - Free zones, 1915-1921 (Box 79, Folder 224-228)
    - Revisions, 1894-1936 (Box 79, Folder 229-234)
  - Yale University
    - Alumni meetings, 1893 (Box 80, Folder 235)
    - Building of Wright Hall, 1910 (Box 80, Folder 236)
    - Class of 1887 history (Box 80, Folder 237-238)
    - Miscellaneous papers, 1921-1923 (Box 80, Folder 239)
    - Student publications, 1846-1887 (Box 80, Folder 240)
    - Undergraduate memorabilia, 1883-1887 (Box 80, Folder 241)
  - Wine bill, 1913-1916 (Box 80, Folder 242)
- BIOGRAPHICAL FILES, 1768-1950; Series IV; 1.25' (3 boxes)
  This series is arranged in four sections: Writings; Genealogical Papers; Memorabilia; Typescript Letters.
  - Writings
    - "Life of William Kent," by Gilson Gardner, [ca. 1933] (Box 81, Folder 243-251)
    - Biography of William Kent, by Elizabeth Thacher Kent, 1950 (Box 81, Folder 252-253)
    - Biography of William Kent (drafts), by Elizabeth Thacher Kent, [ca. 1941] (Box 82, Folder 254-256)
    - "Biography of Elizabeth T. Kent", 1949 (Box 82, Folder 257)
  - Genealogical Papers, 1920-1947 (Box 82, Folder 258-260)
  - Memorabilia, 1768, 1867, 1902-1946 (Box 82, Folder 261-267)
  - Memorabilia (Box 83, Folder 268-270)
  - Typescript Letters, 1918-1928 (Box 83, Folder 271-280)
- MISCELLANEA, 1845-1943; Series V; .75' (2 boxes)
  This series is arranged by record type or creator.
  - Kent, A. E.: telegraph messages, 1875-1876 (Box 84, Folder 281-284)
  - Kent, William
    - The Critic, Hopkins Grammar School, 1881-1883 (Box 84, Folder 285)
    - Ledger, 1881 (Box 84, Folder 286)
    - No folder
  - Photographs
    - Kent, Adaline, [ca. 1860-1910] (Box 85, Folder 288)
    - Kent, William, [ca. 1890-1920] (Box 85, Folder 289)
    - Kent-others, [ca. 1845-1943] (Box 85, Folder 290-291)
    - Album, 1890-1900 (Box 85, Folder 292)
  - Scrapbook-Kent, Elizabeth Thacher, 1883-1887 (Box 85, Folder 293)
- MICROFILM HIST. MSS. 105
  - NUMBER SERIES
    - Kent, William, 1864-1928, compiler, Scrapbooks, 1866-1952, undated
      - Vol I. LITERARY:
        - 1. Cicero's Commonwealth; Some Sides of Homer; Roland series; Slang, etc. (Box 1)
        - 2. Copy and notes for book (Box 1)
        - 3. Scrapbook: Outdoors; Publicity as a Factor; Who are the Anarchists; poems, stories, verse. (Box 1)
      - Vol II. POLITICAL LITERATURE
        - 1. Scrapbook: Letters that Came; Democratic Plank; National Correspondence "Controversies" McVeagh, Ringer; The Problem of Dealing with Vice and Crime in Great Cities. (Box 1)
      - Vol III. CIVIC MATTERS, 1884-1909
        - 1. Scrapbook: Corporal Punishment; Forestry; Civil Service; Tamalpias Park; Lincoln Center; Chicago Half Free. (Box 1)
      - Vol IV. BIOGRAPHICAL
        - 1. Scrapbook: Yerkes, Madden, Lorimer, Harrison, Waller, Ela, Philpot. (Box 1)
      - Vol V. YALE UNIVERSITY
        - 1. Addresses: Yale in Morals; Bicentennial Issue; "My educated mate," "To the Corporation," The Barracks "93" "Working for the City" (Box 1)
      - Vol VI. LOCAL POLITICS, 1896-1907
        - 1. Scrapbook: Chicago: Campaigns: Harlan, Brenner; Potter; Letters; Mann. (Box 1)
      - Vol VII. MUNICIPAL AFFAIRS
        - 1. Certain reports of the Municipal Voters League; Editorial Comments; Publicity as a Factor; Traction Problems (Box 2)
        - 2. Clippings on the Humphrey Bill Uproar; Discussions concerning reform; Constructive legislation and questions of the General Good; Politics only as related to securing results. (Box 2)
      - Vol VIII. INCOMPLETE AND SUGGESTIVE
        - 1. Scrapbook: Paulite; The Confused West; D. B. Hill, Idea of God (Hebrews, Greeks, Calvin); A Couple of Hacks; The Snake; The Lunkhead; Old Letters; The Meanest Old Cuss in Nevada; To a Tramp; The Hills of Mammon, and many others. (Box 2)
      - Vol IX. GENERAL MISCELLANEOUS
        - 1. Envelope: "Chicago: Half Free and fighting On; the Daily Dreadnaught; Gitten Up; Harrisons's Opinion of S. R. Franchises; Jerome; Municipal Politics; Tamalpais National, Park. (Box 2)
        - 2. Scrapbook: Obituary, Albert Emmet Kent; old Age's Lambent Peaks; Vote LaMonte Down; Articles by Washburn; Editorials on Yerkes and Madden; Clippings on local campaigns. (Box 2)
      - Vol X. GOVERNOR YATES
        - 1. Scrapbooks: State Institutions; Addresses and Newspaper Comment; Letter to Yates and Alschuler; various notes. (Missing at the time of filming) (Box 2)
      - Vol XI. CHICAGO POLICE DEPARTMENT, CONGRESSIONAL SCRAPBOOK
        - List of Measures to be discussed:
          - 1. Revision of rules (Box 3)
          - 2. Tariff Revision: wool, cotton, chemical, metal, sugar, olive oil, Lemon Free List Bill(2) (Box 3)
          - 3. Election of Senators by direct vote of the people.(3) (Box 3)
          - 4. Publicity of campaign expenses (4) (Box 3)
          - 5. Admission of Arizona and New Mexico (5) (Box 3)
          - 6. Eight hour law (7) (Box 3)
          - 7. Law preventing abuse of the right of the use of the injunction(8) (Box 3)
          - 8. Three year homestead law (9) (Box 3)
          - 9. Law for relief of homestead entrymen under the reclamation projects (10) (Box 3)
          - 10. Child Bureau (11) (Box 3)
          - 11. Phosphorous Bill (12) (Box 3)
          - 12. Abrogation of the Russian Treaty (6) (Box 3)
          - 13. Amendment to law establishing bureau of mines to extend its operations in metalliferous mining (13) (Box 3)
          - 14. Panama Canal Bill (21) (Box 3)
          - 15. Excise Law (16) (Box 3)
          - 16. Home rule in territory of Alaska (26) (Box 3)
          - 17. Parcels Post (included in Post Office appropriation bill) (Box 3)
          - 18. Pension bills (14) (Box 3)
          - 19. Trial by jury in contempt cases when alleged to be committed without the view of the court. "An act to codify, revise and amend laws relating to the judiciary" (23) (Box 3)
          - 20. Bills suppressing pernicious practice of gambling in agriculture (25) (Box 3)
          - 21. Workmen's compensation Bill (pending) (Box 3)
          - 22. Immigration (15) (Box 3)
          - 23. Regulation of loans in district (pending) (Box 3)
          - 24. Army appropriation bill (17) (Box 3)
          - 25. Navy appropriation bill (18) (Box 3)
          - 26. Agricultural appropriation bill (20) (Box 3)
          - 27. Post-Office appropriation bill (19) (Box 3)
          - 28. San Francisco Mint (Legislative bill) (22) (Box 3)
          - 29. Impeaching Judge Archibald (21) (Box 3)
          - 30. Seal Industry (Box 3)
          - 31. Water power Bills (27) (Box 3)
          - 32. Seamen's Bill (28) (Box 3)
          - 33. Crazing lands bill (50) (Dept. of Labor) (Box 3)
          - 34. Expatriation of Agriculture (Box 3)
        - BILLS INTRODUCED BY MR. KENT (surveys)
          - a. Belvedere Cove (Box 3)
          - b. San Rafael Creek (Box 3)
          - c. Sacramento River (Box 3)
          - d. Corte Madera Channel (Box 3)
          - e. Point Arena Lighthouse Road (Box 3)
          - f. Petaluma River (Box 3)
          - g. San Rafael Creek (Box 3)
        - PETITIONS INTRODUCED BY MR. KENT
          - h. Barth, Wm. (Box 3)
          - i. Cloer, James H. Inc. (Box 3)
          - j. Mixon, Jno. C. Inc. (Box 3)
          - k. Dixon, Napoleon B. (Box 3)
          - l. Medberry, Wm. C. Inc. (Box 3)
          - m. Mitchel, James H., Inc. (Box 3)
          - n. Ream, Noah Y. Inc. (Box 3)
          - o. Smallpage, Sam, Inc. (Box 3)
          - P. Youngman, Alden, Inc. (Box 3)
        - 36. Tariff Legislation, Wool (Box 3)
        - 37. Loan business (Box 3)
        - 38. Good Roads (Box 3)
        - 39. Parcels Post (Box 3)
        - 40. Postal Employees Petition (Box 3)
        - 41. Remarks by Mr. Kent on:
          - a. Service Pensions (Box 3)
          - b. Treaty with Russia homestead tabulation (Box 3)
        - 42. BILLS INTRODUCED BY MR. KENT
          - a. Expatriation, 20349, 21358, 24120 (Box 3)
          - b. State game preserves for protection and increase of (Box 3)
        - 43. Pensions
          - a. Carpenter, Frminia Thayer (Box 3)
          - b. Devol Norman (Box 3)
          - c. Rushton, George H. Remove charge of desertion (Box 3)
          - d. Merchant, Frederick F. (Box 3)
          - e. Kneedlerm, Thomas B. (Box 3)
        - 44. Claims
          - a. Cynthia R. Ball (Box 3)
          - b. Davis, Ira (Box 3)
        - 45. Remarks on by Mr. Kent
          - a. San Francisco Mint (Box 3)
          - b. Davis Canal (Box 3)
          - c. Powder for Navy (Box 3)
  - LETTER SERIES, 1911-1915
    - Scrapbook "A"
      [This material consists mainly of clippings; index is that of William Kent]
      - 1. Personal, 1911-1912; 1914-1915 (Box 4)
      - 2. Mrs. A. E. Kent, 1912-1914 (Box 4)
      - 3. Grape Festival, 1911-1914 (Box 4)
      - 4. Marin County News, 1911-1915 (Box 4)
      - 5. Muir Woods Road, 1913-1914 (Box 4)
      - 6. Mt. Tamalpais Roads, 1914-1915 (Box 4)
      - 7. Water Supply, Marin County, 1911-1915 (Box 4)
      - 8. Yale, 1912-1915 (Box 4)
      - 9. Anecdotes, Miscellaneous, 1912-1915 (Box 4)
      - 10. Popular Government League, 1913 (Box 4)
      - 11. Golconda Cattle Company, 1912-1914 (Box 4)
      - 12. Chicago Politics, 1914 (Box 4)
      - 13. Hearst, 1914 (Box 4)
      - 14. Carl Browne, 1915-1914 (Box 4)
      - 15. Governor Pinkham, of Hawaii, and Hawaiian Politics, 1911-1913 (Box 4)
      - 16. Francis Burton Harrison, Gov. Gen., Phil. Is., 1913 (Box 4)
      - 17. Miscellaneous: Sen. Geo. S. Nixon, Nevada; Jack Sibbald, 1912-1913 (Box 4)
    - Scrapbook "B"
      - 1. Panama Canal Tolls, 1911-1914 (Box 4)
      - 2. Battleships, 1912-1914 (Box 4)
      - 3. Immigration, 1912-1914 (Box 4)
      - 4. Good Roads, 1913-1914 (Box 4)
      - 5. Democracy and Efficiency, 1913-1914 (Box 4)
      - 6. Powder Resolution; Munitions of War, 1913-1915 (Box 4)
      - 7. Woman Suffrage, 1911-1915 (Box 4)
      - 8. Bald Rock National Park, 1913 (Box 4)
      - 9. Rocky Mountain National Park, 1914 (Box 4)
      - 10. Mt. Lassen National Park, 1915 (Box 4)
    - Scrapbook "C"
      [This list consists almost entirely of clippings; index is W.K.]
      - 1. First district Post offices and Rural Routes, 1912 (Box 4)
      - 2. Chinese eggs and other egg matters, 1914 (Box 4)
      - 3. Civic and other clubs, first district, 1911-1913 (Box 4)
      - 4. Sacramento and Feather River, 1912-1915 (Box 4)
      - 5. Duxbury Life Saving Station, 1915 (Box 4)
      - 6. Humboldt Jetties, 1913-1915 (Box 4)
      - 7. Petaluma Creek improvement 1911-1914 (Box 4)
      - 8. Dry Dock, Marin county, 1913-1915 (Box 4)
      - 9. Contra Costa County Dry Dock, 1914 (Box 4)
      - 10. San Rafael channe1, 1911-1914, 1915 (Box 4)
      - 11. Corte Madera Channel, 1912-1914 (Box 4)
      - 12. Sausalito Ferry, 1914 (Box 4)
      - 13. Novato Creek 1913-1915 (Box 4)
      - 14. Belvedere, 1911-1912 (Box 4)
      - 15. Redwood Park, Humboldt County, 1913-1914 (Box 4)
      - 16. Free seeds and documents, 1912-1915 (Box 4)
      - 17. Yearbooks, 1912 (Box 4)
      - 18. West Point Military Academy, 1911-1914 (Box 4)
    - Scrapbook "D"
      - 1. Southern Pacific, 1911-1912 (Box 4)
      - 2. Hetch hetchy, 1913 (Box 4)
      - 3. Foot and Mouth Disease, 1915 (Box 4)
      - 4. Miscellaneous State Matters, 1911-1913 (Box 4)
      - 5. California State Politics, 1911-1915 (Box 4)
      - 6. U.S. Senator from California, 1911-1915 (Box 4)
      - 7. California State Politics, 1911-1912 (Box 4)
      - 8. Francis J. Heney, 1912-1914 (Box 4)
      - 9. Hiram W. Johnson, 1912-1914 (Box 4)
      - 10. California Election Laws, 1911-1915 (Box 4)
      - 11. Redistricting of California, 1911-1912 (Box 4)
      - 12. National Post Office, matters, 1912-1914 (Box 4)
      - 13. Recall, 1911-1912 (Box 4)
      - 14. Recreation and Playground Work, 1911-1914 (Box 4)
      - 15. Rural Credits, 1914 (Box 4)
      - 16. Butte County News, 1914-1915 (Box 4)
      - 17. Butte County Federal Building, 1914 (Box 4)
      - 18. Sutter Country, 1912 (Box 4)
      - 19. Colusa County Post Offices and Rural Routes (Box 4)
      - 20. Marin County Post Offices and Rural Routes (Box 4)
      - 21. Humboldt County Post Offices and Rural Routes (Box 4)
      - 22. Humboldt County Affairs, 1913-1915 (Box 4)
      - 23. Yuba County Federal Buildings, 1914 (Box 4)
      - 24. Yuba County News, 1914 (Box 4)
      - 25. Sonoma County Federal Buildings, 1914 (Box 4)
      - 26. Sonoma County News, 1913-1914 (Box 4)
      - 27. Often County Federal Buildings and Rural Routes, 1913-1915 (Box 4)
      - 28. Mendocino County News, 1912-1914 (Box 4)
      - 29. Lake County News, 1911-1914 (Box 4)
      - 30. Del Norte County News, 1914-1915 (Box 4)
    - Scrapbook "E"
      - 1. Wilson Administration, 1912-1915 (Box 5)
      - 2. Monroe Doctrine (Box 5)
      - 3. National Politics, 1911-1915 (Box 5)
      - 4. Tariff, 1911-1912 (Box 5)
      - 5. Reciprocity, 1911 (Box 5)
      - 6. Tariff Bill, 1913-1915 (Box 5)
      - 7. Wool Schedule, 1911-1912 (Box 5)
      - 8. Sugar Schedule, 1912-1913 (Box 5)
      - 9. Steel Schedule, 1912 (Box 5)
      - 10. Olive oil, 1912 (Box 5)
      - 11. Mexico, 1913-1914 (Box 5)
    - Scrapbook "F"
      [This consists almost entirely of clippings kept by W.K.; index is his own.]
      - 1. Water Power bill, 1914 (Box 5)
      - 2. Crazing Bill, 1912-1914 (Box 5)
      - 3. Conservation, 1914-1915 (Box 5)
      - 4. Oil Lands Bill, 1913-1914 (Box 5)
      - 5. Alaska Coal, 1911 (Box 5)
      - 6. Radium, 1914 (Box 5)
      - 7. Seamen's Bill, 1913-1914 (Box 5)
      - 8. National Marketing, 1915 (Box 5)
      - 9. Poultry, 1915 (Box 5)
      - 10. Price of meat, 1912-1914 (Box 5)
      - 11. Ship-purchase Bill, 1913-1915 (Box 5)
      - 12. Wine interests, 1913-1914 (Box 5)
      - 13. Prohibition, 1912-1914 (Box 5)
      - 14. Nursery inspection, 1912-1915 (Box 5)
      - 15. Peace Movement, 1914 (Box 5)
      - 16. Panama-Pacific Exposition, 1913-1915 (Box 5)
      - 17. Japanese Exclusion, 1913-1915 (Box 5)
      - 18. Pension Bill, 1911-1912 (Box 5)
      - 19. San Francisco Mint, 1912 (Box 5)
      - 20. Kent Bill (6 year term for congressmen) (Box 5)
      - 21. Woman's Citizenship Bill, 1912-1913 (Box 5)
      - 22. Government Ownership Telephone and Telegraph Lines, 1913 (Box 5)
      - 23. Parcels Post, 1912-1913 (Box 5)
      - 24. Borah Homestead Bill and Homestead Laws, 1912-1914 (Box 5)
      - 25. Tax on mail order houses, 1913 (Box 5)
    - Scrapbook "G"
      - Tariff Speech, 1911 (Box 6)
      - Seeds, 1911 (Box 6)
      - Charles W. Cobb, 1911 (Box 6)
      - Golconda Cattle Company (Box 6)
      - Duncan Mckinley (Box 6)
      - Peace Treaties (Box 6)
      - Alaska Coal Mines (Box 6)
      - Reapportionment Bill (Box 6)
      - North Carolina Land (Box 6)
      - Panama-Pacific Exposition (Box 6)
      - Conservation (Box 6)
      - Russian Treaty (Box 6)
      - Lake Tahoe (Box 6)
      - Hetch-Hetchy Water Rights (Box 6)
      - San. Rafael Creek (Box 6)
      - Breakwater, Monterey Bay (Box 6)
      - Panama Canal Tolls (Box 6)
      - Sacramento River (Box 6)
      - Postal Matters (Box 6)
      - Pension Legislation (Box 6)
      - Annapolis Academy (Box 6)
      - Arizona and New Mexico (Box 6)
      - California Redistricting (Box 6)
      - Recall (Box 6)
      - Constitutional Amendments (Direct Legislation) (Box 6)
      - Suffrage (Box 6)
      - Chinese Immigrants (Box 6)
      - LaFollette for President, 1912 (Box 6)
      - Insurgency and Insurgents (Box 6)
    - Scrapbook "H"
      - Alien Land Laws (Asiatic Exclusion) (Box 6)
      - Appointments, Service Academies (Box 6)
      - Banking and Currency (Box 6)
      - Cattle Case (Golcondo Company) (Box 6)
      - Cattle on the Border (Box 6)
      - California Affairs:
        - Governor Hiram Johnson (Box 6)
        - Fruit Crop (Box 6)
        - Sacramento Project (Box 6)
        - Spring Valley (Box 6)
        - Feather River (Box 6)
        - Quarantine Law (Box 6)
        - California Appointments (Box 6)
        - Dredging (Box 6)
        - Tamalpais and Lake Tahoe (Box 6)
        - Marin Dry Dock (Box 6)
      - Cabinet, Kent for (Chicago Convention) (Box 6)
      - Campaign 1912 (Box 6)
      - Flood Relief (Box 6)
      - Immigration (Box 6)
      - Navy (Box 6)
      - Panama Appropriation (Box 6)
      - Public Lands Bill (Box 6)
      - Social and Personal (Box 6)
      - Tariff (Box 6)
      - Third Party - Wilson Administration (Box 6)
      - U'Ren and the Glavis Libel Suit (Box 6)
      - Wilson (President) (Box 6)
      - Zumwalt Contest (Box 6)
  - CONGRESSIONAL SERIES
    - Scrapbook of clippings: William Kent for Senator, 1920 (Box 7)
    - Campaign literature, 1910 (Box 7)
    - Congressional measures, 1911-1913 (Box 7)
  - CHRONOLOGICAL SERIES
    - Yale scrapbook, Elizabeth Thacher kent, 1883-1885 (Box 8)
    - Yale, 1866-1884 (Box 8)
    - Yale, 1883-1884 (Box 8)
    - Political clippings, 1896-1897, 1906-1911 (Box 8)
    - General miscellaneous, 1906-1911 (Box 8)
    - Elizabeth Thacher Kent Appointment calenders, 1912-1952 (Box 8)
    - Muir Woods, Tamalpais National Park, Tamalpais Game Reserve, Marin County Items, 1908-1911 (Box 9)
    - Political clippings, 1918-1920 (Box 9)
    - Clippings from California papers relating to Kent's 1910 campaign for, and election to Congress., 1910 May-December (Box 10)
    - Clippings from California newspapers re: Kent's campaign for the Republican nomination and then for election to Congress from the 2nd District in California., 1910 May-November (Box 11)
    - Clippings from California, New York, and Chicago newspapers relating to Kent's campaign for election (1910) and to California politics., 1910-1913 (Box 12)
    - Clippings from California papers showing Kent's political position on various issues., 1912 January-1913 December (Box 13)
    - Excerpts from the U.S. Congressional Record that refer to national land use legislation. 26 pp., 1913 (Box 13)
    - Notice of a California primary election in the Chico Daily Enterprise., 1914 August 4 (Box 13)
    - A pamphlet entitled, William Kent's Record in Congress by Franklin Hitchborn. 16 pp., 1912 (Box 13)
    - Clippings from California newspapers including the following items:
      - William Kent's Report to the People of the District., 1914 August 1 (Box 13)
      - Humboldt Times (California) editorials in support of Kent's campaign for Congress., 1914 August 23 (Box 13)
      - A sample ballot for the 1st District of California., 1914 (Box 13)
    - Clippings from California and other papers concerning the following issues:
      - Activities and political positions of Congressman Kent., 1916 (Box 13)
      - National Parks., 1916 (Box 13)
      - Arms Control., 1915-1916 (Box 13)
      - A Naval Academy on the West Coast., 1915-1916 (Box 13)
      - Political controversy and scandal relating to Congressman Kent., 1915-1916 (Box 13)
    - Clippings from California newspapers referring to Kent's political activities and 1912 campaign for Congress., 1911-1912 (Box 13)